Guide to the Cayuga Bird Club Records, 1913-1997
Cayuga Bird Club Records, 1913-1997
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cayuga Bird Club records, 1913-1997
1996
Cayuga Bird Club.
1.4 cubic ft.
Minutes, correspondence, financial records, clippings, photographs, and printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes, correspondence, financial records, clippings, photographs, and printed material concerning the Cayuga Bird Club. Includes the club's constitution (ca. 1913) and papers of incorporation (1914); Arthur Allen's article "Cayuga Bird Club"; and correspondence of Louis Agassiz Fuertes, the club's first president, including letters to him from Jared T. Newman concerning Renwick Woodland improvement.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Cayuga Bird Club was founded ca. 1913. Its first secretary was Arthur A. Allen; Louis Agassiz Fuertes served as the first president. Charter members included Liberty Hyde Bailey, Martha Van Rensselaer, Prof. William A. Stocking, Mynderse Van Cleef, and Prof. Walter F. Willcox.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes, correspondence, financial records, clippings, photographs, and printed material concerning the Cayuga Bird Club. Includes the club's constitution (ca. 1913) and papers of incorporation (1914); Arthur Allen's article "Cayuga Bird Club," which provides an early history of the Club and was probably published in Bird Lore; and correspondence of Louis Agassiz Fuertes, the club's first president, including letters to him from Jared T. Newman concerning Renwick Woodland improvement. Also, newsletters, 1989-1997, by-laws, newspaper clippings, membership lists, and receipts.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cayuga Bird Club.; Allen, Arthur A. (Arthur Augustus), 1885-1964.; Fuertes, Louis Agassiz, 1874-1927.; Newman, Jared T. (Jared Treman), 1855-1937.
Subjects:
Ornithology.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
The papers of the Cayuga Bird Club were part of the original Arthur A. Allen accession.
RELATED MATERIAL
Related collections: Hugh Daniel Reed Papers, #21\18\33 and Arthur A. Allen Papers, #21\18\1255.
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondences, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Financial Records and Statements, 1913-1918, 1923, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cayuga Bird Club (CBC) Constitution, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Certificate of Incorporation, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondences, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1915-1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondences, 1915-1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Meeting Announcements, 1916-1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Financial Records, 1916-1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Yearly Reports, 1918-1929 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bills and Statements, 1926-1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- National Audubon News Releases, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- CBC Committee Reports, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Audubon, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Receipts and Misc. Correspondences, 1940-1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bank Statements, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- CBC Treasurer Report, 1974-1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- CBC Ledger Sheets, 1974-1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Federation of NY Bird Clubs, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Bank Statements, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- CBC Address List, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Federation of NY Bird Clubs - 37th Annual Meeting, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Federation of NY Bird Clubs - 37th Annual Meeting - Registration, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 23-25)
- Federation of NY Bird Clubs - 37th Annual Meeting - Sheraton and Forms, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Federation of NY Bird Clubs - 37th Annual Meeting - Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27-30)
- CBC Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
- Federation of NY Bird Clubs - 37th Annual Meeting Accounts, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Federation of NY Bird Clubs - 37th Annual Meeting Finances, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Bank Statements, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Richard Evans Memorial, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- CBC Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Bank Statements, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- CBC President's File, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- CBC President's File, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- CBC President's File, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- CBC President's File, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- CBC President's File, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Cayuga Bird Club Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Newsletter, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Newsletters, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Newsletters, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Newsletters, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Newsletters, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Newsletters, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Newsletters, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Newsletters, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Newsletters, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Newsletters, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Newsletters, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Newsletters, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Newsletters, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Newsletters, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Newsletters, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Newsletters, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Newsletters, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Newsletters, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Newsletters, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Newsletters, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Membership Book, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Book of Minutes, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Ledger, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Daybook, 1913-1936 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miscellaenous, 1916, 1976, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)